Jimmy Hotchkiss | GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn

San Anselmo, CA 94960 561-704-5894 jimmy.hotchkiss@gmail.com

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full stack web developer experienced in Ruby on Rails and React/Redux based programming and experience as a quality engineer in the medical device industry. Demonstrated strong skills in leadership and project building that help launch an app used by an entire endoscopy sales force.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, Javascript, SQL, HTML, CSS Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, React, Redux

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Lead Tracker CMS - Github-api | Github-client | Demo

Custom Content Management System (CMS) project built with React and Rails API

- Applied Redux and Redux-Thunk to properly maintain the state while making asynchronies fetch request
- Implemented client-side routing by using React-Router for accurate RESTful routing
- Leveraged Rails sessions and cookies to properly log the user in and out of the CMS application.
- Utilized Material UI to create an engaging display of user data.

The Vegan Cow - Github | Demo

Recipe Content Management System (CMS) built with a vanilla Javascript frontend and a Rails API backend

- Integrated Javascript and Rails to implement features that reached across frontend and backend
- Leveraged AJAX calls to establish client-server communication
- Encapsulated related data and behavior by utilizing Object Oriented Javascript

Project Manager - Github Live Demo

A project management system for developers to create and keep track of the progress built with Ruby on Rails

- Leveraged Active Record associations to build a powerful and scalable application
- Applied MVC best practices to assure a robust development environment and performance
- Deployed Ominauth to handle user authentication safely through Google.
- Implemented partials to minimize repeat code and keep code base DRY

EXPERIENCE

Stryker Assoc. Quality Engineer San Jose, CA 09/2021 - Present

- Working cross-functionally to maintain the health of the repair process from materials to technical needs
- Work cross-functionally to maintain and update app used by sales force

Stryker

San Jose, CA

Sr. Technical Support Representative

12/2018 - 09/2021

- Contribute to product development by influencing product improvements and technology advances.
- Work cross-functionally to develop, build and deploy software solutions for internal customers.

Stryker OnSite Specialist

Seattle, WA 11/2017 – 12/2018

Provided end-to-end surgical equipment management and technical support

Provided clinical support during surgical cases and education and guidance to clinical staff.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

OnLine

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rail and Javascript prom

04/2017 - 04/2021

University of Florida

Gainesville, FL 05/2016

Masters Astronomy

Florida Atlantic University BA Physics – Magna Cum Laude Boca Raton, FL 05/2014